analysts feel icici lombard is said to
deliver robust growth in the
since 2008 the general insurance
industry has shown a 14-year path cagr
of 2.4 percent whereas icici lombard
delivered a 22.7 cagr during the same
period such superior long-term growth is
supported by
disciplined underwriting sustainable
value creation and excellence in
customer service in 2021 2021-22
the company reported a gdpi of rupees 17
977 crore a growth of 28.4 percent year
on year
so here are the reasons why analysts
remain confident about the prospects of
the company the possibilities of the
industry are improving due to a change
in the consumer's perception of health
insurance the kobit 19 panel
so what has triggered the industry
growth
first the availability of digital online
options for policy issuance and claims
a growing middle class
and young insurable population along
with the continued regulator efforts to
make insurance affordable with tighter
norms to protect customer interest
second the company is likely to witness
growth across varied segments the
revival of auto sector is expected to
support its motor insurance segment
easing supply side issues rising demand
for cvs and a likely jump in demand for
two wheelers due to opening of the
offices and colleges are among the few
icici lombard has already increased its
sales force and expanding its
distribution network to increase
penetration in tier 3 and 4 cities the
company also sees market share
aggression in commercial segments like
fire engineering and marine
third the company will benefit from
strong synergies from bharti axa merger
the merger was completed in 2122
and synergy benefits of rupees 200 crore
are expected out of which to be 70 crore
has been realized in 2122. the fourth
point is that the company plans to
continue expansion across distribution
digital technology and claim services it
has planned additional investment in the
range of rupees 100 to 150 crore in
2223. according to the motilal oswald
report the stock has significantly
underperformed the market benchmark last
year
as a result it is trading near an
all-time low on a one-year forward
valuation the negative aspect is that
the adverse regulatory policy aggressive
pricing by peers and impact on pricing
power due to rising competition are the
key risks for icici lombard
[Music]
you